

# **Hugo Dorfling**

**Product Engineer** 

Location: Date of Birth: Languages:

Email: About me:

South Africa 1995 / 03 / 15 English & Afrikaans (HL) hugodorfling@live.co.za www.hugo.dorfling.org

#### **Education**

#### Certifications

- · Certified Scrum Product Owner + Certified Scrum Master + A-CSM (Scrum Alliance)
- AWS Developer Associate
- · AWS Solutions Architect Associate
- · AWS Cloud Practitioner
- CompTIA A+ & N+
- freeCodeCamp

# **University of London**

#### **BSc Computer Science**

· Attending from Oct. 2021 (5 subjects done)

#### **University of Pretoria**

# BCom Informatics (1st year -Incomplete)

- Attended from Jan. 2017 to Nov. 2017
- · Left to work full-time in IT to pivot to Computer Science studies
- 83.20% average semester 1

# Hoërskool Eldoraigne

# **National Senior Certificate**

- High school education from Jan. 2009 to Dec. 2013
- 87% average final mark

#### **Personal Profile**

I have 3+ years of experience in Digital Product Development from 3 different startups (Seed & Development, Startup and Growth business stages respectively). I served in roles of Technical Product Manager, Full Stack Engineer, Front-End Engineer, UI & UX (Figma & Miro) and Cloud Engineer with Agile Scrum and Kanban product development frameworks.

I have done some studies in BCom Informatics and BSc Computer Science, both incomplete degrees, and discovered through practical work experience, on real products, that I truly excel in the Product Engineer role.

I combine skills gained in the multiple key roles of a product team, and strive to create value through leading and serving on teams that are dedicated to creating life-changing products that have a positive impact.

# **Career Summary**

# **Software Engineer**

- Front-End Development (Data Viz)
- OAuth2 REST API's in NestJS
- App Redesign (UX/UI & Implementation)
- Material UI v4 to MUI v5 upgrade

#### Klar Insights GmbH (Apr. 2022 to Sep. 2022)

React, TypeScript, MUI v5, Styled Components, AG-Grid, i18next, Redux, Plotly, Git (GitHub), Husky, ESLint, Sentry, Axios, data-forge, React Hook Form, Helmet, Socket.io, Cypress, Jest, NestJS, OAuth2, Figma, Miro, Slack

#### Software Engineer Synthesis Software Technologies (Sep. 2020 to Mar. 2022)

- Full-stack Software development and design of FinTech products
- SaaS and Cloud Native
- Product design (UX/UI)
- Product management

React, TypeScript, Material UI v4, Styled Components, Redux, Apexcharts, AWS Services, Highcharts, Prime React, Husky, ESLint, Axios, Git (Bitbucket), .Net Core, Entity Framework, DDD, MySQL, Terraform, Figma, Miro, MS Teams

# **Product Manager**

· Tasked to ensure success of the company buying and taking over the IP of their cashless system software

Customer feedback & satisfaction,

collaboration, servant leadership,

user experience, outcome based

business value generation,

- Product management
- Agile product delivery

Strong focus:

Product Management, Technical Product Support, Release Notes, Help Documentation, Agile Scrum

Howler (Jul. 2019 to Feb. 2020)

• • • LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/leslie-hugo-dorfling/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/leslie-hugo-dorfling/</a>

#### **Professional Skills**

# **Key Competencies:**

Digital Product development & management, Discovery, Prototyping & Analysis, Design, Technical Skill, Front-End Web

#### Soft skills:

Leadership, Active listening, Empathy, Collaboration & Teamwork, Critical thinking, Mediator, Stakeholder management, Assertive, Strong Communicator (Written & Verbal), Strong interpersonal skills (flexible & tolerant), Negotiation, Influencing, Fast learner, Strong analytical problemsolving ability, Planning, Analysis, Time management

Product Owner. Howler in 2020

# Tools/Processes:

Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Confluence, Miro (Whiteboarding), Figma (Design & Prototyping), Monday, Notion

Web Development (SaaS). Cloud (AWS), Musician (Guitar, Singing, Production), Social Responsibility, Spirituality